CHEN HE

□ (+33) 665345913 | Schen.he.95@outlook.com | Ocher-en-95 | Chen.he95 | Schen.he95 | Chen.he95 | Chen

CAREER SUMMARY

Current PhD student at Mines Saint-Etienne. 3+ years experience specializing in data intelligence and machine learning. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for data-driven decision making tasks and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises. **Personality traits**: Excellent written and verbal communication skills, Excellent analytical skills, Leadership and team player skill, Ability to work under pressure.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Languages: English (full professional proficiency with TOEIC Listening and Reading Test 800), French (professional working proficiency, B2 level), Mandarin (native proficiency)

Programming: Python, R, Java, C++, Git, Unix shell scripting, Spark, Hadoop.

DBMS: MySOL, SQL server, AWS, NoSQL, HiveQL, Spark SQL.

Data-driven modeling: Classification, Regression, Clustering, Association Rule Mining, Anomaly Detection, Deep Learning, Mathematical programming, Bayesian inference, Recommender systems.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE_

Mines Saint-Etienne · Fully funded PhD program

St-Étienne, France

PHD STUDENT IN INDUSTRIAL ENGINEERING

Oct. 2019 - Oct. 2022

- Completed two research projects in health management & data intelligence, published two papers in international Conferences and journals.
- · Worked as a graduate teaching assistant (TA), performed all TA duties including mentoring, lecturing and clerical work.
- · Technologies: Python, Shell scripting.

Hubert Curien Laboratory · Internship

St-Étienne, France

MACHINE LEARNING TRAINEE IN DATA INTELLIGENCE TEAM

Feb. 2019 - Sep. 2019

- A quantitative study of CNN parameters' precision variation on classification performance (i.e., inference speed and accuracy) for a image classification task on FPGAs.
- Implemented a GAN (Generative Adversarial Network) framework for contours detection.
- Technologies: Python, Tensorflow, Shell scripting.

XXII Group · Internship

Paris, France

MACHINE LEARNING TRAINEE IN R & D DEPARTMENT

Jul. 2018 - Sep. 2018

- Optimized a pedestrian detection project including hyper-parameter tuning, loss function and SGD algorithm optimization.
- Improved model's inference speed from 12 to 22 FPS on Nvidia Jetson TX2 with NVIDIA TensorRT.
- Implemented multiple docker images for deploying the pedestrian detection project to Nvidia Jetson TX2.
- Technologies: Python, Yolo, Docker, Shell scripting.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

News filtering project · Telecom Saint-Etienne

St-Etienne, France

AUTOMATIC ANALYSIS OF FINANCIAL NEWS AND FILTERING NEWS RELATED TO THE EARNING OF COMPANIES, [CODE].

Oct. 2018

- · Contributed expertise in NLP and Machine Learning including word embedding, classification, performance evaluation, etc.
- Technologies: Word embedding (TF-IDF, N-gram), Classification.

Repayment ability prediction project · Telecom Saint-Etienne

St-Etienne, France

AUTOMATIC ANALYSIS OF CLIENTS' PROFILE AND PREDICTING THEIR REPAYMENT ABILITY, [CODE].

Jul. 2018

- · Contributed expertise in risk modeling and in particular predicting clients' repayment ability by a logit model.
- Technologies: Dimension reduction, Logistic regression, NoSQL Hadoop.

EDUCATION

Mines Saint-Etienne (2019-2022): PhD in <u>Industrial Engineering</u> applied to Healthcare. Research topic: "mining, understanding, and optimizing medical miscoding behaviors for coding practice improvement.". Thesis director: Prof. <u>Xiaolan Xie</u>.

Jean Monnet University (2018-2019): A double master's degree (M.S.) in <u>Data and Connected System.</u>

<u>Telecom Saint-Etienne</u> (2016-2019): Master's degree (M.Eng.) in <u>Computer Science</u> with minor in Big Data and Artificial intelligence,

Xidian University (2013-2017): Bachelor of Engineering (B.Eng.) in Electronic Science and Technology.

APRIL 16, 2022 CHEN HE · RÉSUMÉ